# **James Petty**

Canberra, AU

https://www.jamespetty.com.au | https://www.linkedin.com/in/j-petty | https://github.com/j-petty

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software engineer with 7 years of experience building scalable and maintainable web applications hosted in cloud environments. I specialise in backend development however enjoy maintaining a strong cross-stack skillset with a keen interest in frontend JavaScript frameworks and cloud architecture.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Department of Parliamentary Services**

Senior Web Developer

Jan 2022 - Present

- Technical lead for development of a new committee report builder application used to produce hundreds of parliamentary reports each year, which are then tabled and accessible to the Australian public.
- Integrated with 4 systems including two legacy applications, SharePoint Online and SiteCore CMS.
- Coordinated project risks and dependencies to ensure development, testing, cloud infrastructure, and cyber security teams achieved the committed delivery dates.
- Established automation tools including CI/CD pipelines, linting, static code analysis and unit testing to achieve minimum code coverage of 60%.
- Technologies: .NET, React.js, SQL MI, App Services

# **Attorney-General's Department**

Senior Web Developer

Apr 2021 - Jan 2022

- Led development of a secure legal advice sharing platform now in use across government departments as a single source of truth for hundreds of legal advice documents.
- Coached 2 junior developers while maintaining project's momentum to achieve delivery targets.
- Collaborated closely with product owner to ensure each sprint delivered highest priority features and achieved business outcomes.
- Introduced common .NET and React libraries now shared across the department to drastically improve code maintainability and reuse.
- Technologies: .NET, React.js, Azure

# **Deloitte Digital**

Senior Technical Specialist

Mar 2018 - Apr 2021

- Implemented a web portal for aviation industry personnel to interact with CASA (Civil Aviation Safety Authority), capable of scaling to support 2M users and resulting in a significant reduction in operational expenditure.
- Designed and built a digital pilot license issuing micro-service used by thousands of pilots across Australia.
- Developed a chatbot to improve Services
   Australia's internal IT support platform used by 35K employees, reducing tickets raised by up to 30%.
- Technologies: .NET, React.js, Dynamics CRM, Azure

#### Spinify

Web Developer

Nov 2016 - Mar 2018

- Designed and built gamified leaderboard screens to motivate teams, resulting in an average 43% increase in sales.
- Implemented scalable micro-services backend capable of handling real-time events for thousands of concurrent users.
- Technologies: React.js, Node.js, AWS

#### Made for Me

Web Developer

Sep 2015 - Oct 2016

- Designed and developed public website and contributed to development of online 3D printing quote tool.
- Technologies: Python, Django, AWS

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Information Technology**

University of Canberra

Majors in Software Engineering and Information Systems

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

# **Programming Languages**

C# (expert), TypeScript (expert), HTML5, CSS3, SQL

#### **Frameworks**

ASP.NET (expert), React.js (expert), Entity Framework (expert), Redux, Sass, ESLint, StyleCop

#### Cloud

Azure (expert), Amazon Web Services (experienced), micro-services, event-driven architecture

### **Deployment**

Version control, CI/CD, Azure DevOps (expert), Docker (working knowledge), SonarQube

#### **PROJECTS**

# Recruithero

Jan 2021 - Present

- Co-founder and technical lead of a recruitment start-up aimed at improving the contracting experience for everyone.
- Our focus on TDD (test driven development) and a collaborative user-centered design approach enables fortnightly release cycles that address key customer needs.
- Technologies: .NET micro-services backend, React.js, React Native (iOS), Azure

### MyWay Balance (source)

2020

- Developed a mobile app used by over 2K ACT commuters to check their transport card balance.
- Technologies: Xamarin Forms (.NET)